# **MAY NG**

# FULL STACK SOFTWARF DEVELOPER

### Contact

**™** mngmay@gmail.com

mayng.dev

**(**206) 979-5145

Seattle, WA

**in** mngmay

mngmay

# Skills

Javascript

React

React Hooks

Redux

**HTML** 

CSS

Less

Sass

Node.js Express

Python

**SQL** 

Git

Jest

# **Education**

### Lambda School

05/2019 - Current Full Stack Software Development & Computer Science

#### **University of Washington**

10/2018 - 12/2018

Foundational Databases Course utilizing Microsoft SQL Server

#### Bellevue College

06/2016 - 08/2017

HR Management Certificate Program

### **University of Washington**

09/2008 - 03/2013

B.A. Communication and Chinese Language & Literature

# Summary

Full Stack Software Developer with over 5 years of business experience focused on improving operational effectiveness. Experience in Javascript, React, Node, and Express to build fully functional web applications. Strong communicator with a proven record in bridging the gap between technical teams and their stakeholders.

# **Projects**

#### Pizza Party (https://pizzaparty.netlify.com)

Frontend Developer | React, Context API, CSS Grid, Flexbox, and Styled Components An interactive adventure game that allows players to control their turtle adventurer to navigate sewer passages in search of pizza.

- Collaborated with 1 Frontend Developer and 2 Backend Developers for this 4 day build
- Managed global game state using Context API and hooks for seamless game interactions
- Designed and built intuitive interface for users, including rendered map visualization from backend data

# Wanderlust (https://github.com/Wanderlust-build-week-project/back-end) Backend Architect | Node.js, Express, Knex, SQLite3 /Postgres

A website that showcases a variety of tours in various locations. Connects both customers and tour guides for streamlined search and sign up.

- Worked alongside 1 other Backend Developer for database schema design and creation
- Built a Postgres database and wrote API endpoints within 2 days for quick deliverable to the frontend team
- Applied JSON web token technology to develop user credential authentication

### Lambda Lifts (https://lambdalifts.netlify.com)

Frontend Developer | React, Redux, Sass

A weight lifting application that enables users to create custom work outs with a variety of exercises.

- Contributed to a cross-functional team of 5 developers on a 4 day project
- Designed and managed global state using Redux
- Collaborated closely with UX Designer and Jr. developers on meeting various design criteria to build a beautiful interface

# **Employment**

### Lambda School

Remote 10/2019 - 12/2019

Teaching Assistant

- Managed groups of 5+ students in school curriculum focused on HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Conducted code reviews with students to provide quality feedback and debugging support
- Led group stand-ups on curriculum and conducted code exercises

#### **Robert Half**

Seattle, WA 05/2018 - 05/2019

Contractor • Collaborated with developers to create and test new internal platforms

Identified and escalated areas of concern for process and algorithm improvements

### ChemPoint.com

Human Resources Specialist

Bellevue, WA 06/2013 - 04/2018

- Built a new Employee Resources SharePoint site for the business
- Created reporting for recruitment and retention for executive leadership and management
- Documented SOP across various HR focuses
- Facilitated full cycle recruitment and owned new employee on-boarding